<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments for MirandaNet Research Exchange	</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.mirandanet.org.uk/researchexchange/comments/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.mirandanet.org.uk/researchexchange</link>
	<description>O brave new world that has such people in IT</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2014 17:10:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.15</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		Comment on Miranda&#8217;s ICT curriculum by Ian Lynch		</title>
		<link>https://www.mirandanet.org.uk/researchexchange/publications/articles/ict-curriculum-mirandas-views/our-ict-curriculum/comment-page-1/#comment-15687</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ian Lynch]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 10:40:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.mirandanet.ac.uk/researchexchange/?page_id=3102#comment-15687</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There is no mention of using ICT across the curriculum although I doubt it would be any more sensible not to do so than say isolate English to just specialist lessons. Digital technologies are useless without application. Why learn any technology if it does not result in a practical outcome? That principle applies to computing except perhaps for blue sky research in number theories which has a tiny minority of relevance in schools and would probably be better in the maths department. Even school science departments understand that purely theoretical science has a very limited place in high schools. That is not to say digital technologies do not need specialist input - again English is a good parallel. Learning English is not much use if it does not practically contribute to being able to communicate whether in subject silos or more generally in everyday life. Saying that the aim of an English programme of study is not at least in part to support higher  attainment throughout the curriculum would fly in the face of just about every established education tradition. On team work and leadership, it rather depends on whether you think education is about isolating skills from the ways human beings work. If you think learning facts and instrumental skills is what constitute a rounded education fair enough but I certainly wouldn&#039;t want my grandchildren taught like that. There is some clear precedence for assessing &quot;social skills&quot; in the context of science and technology. The Suffolk Science GCSE course had assessment weight given to effective collaboration between learners in experimental investigation and for good reason. Most major discoveries in science are made by teams, not individuals working in isolation.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There is no mention of using ICT across the curriculum although I doubt it would be any more sensible not to do so than say isolate English to just specialist lessons. Digital technologies are useless without application. Why learn any technology if it does not result in a practical outcome? That principle applies to computing except perhaps for blue sky research in number theories which has a tiny minority of relevance in schools and would probably be better in the maths department. Even school science departments understand that purely theoretical science has a very limited place in high schools. That is not to say digital technologies do not need specialist input &#8211; again English is a good parallel. Learning English is not much use if it does not practically contribute to being able to communicate whether in subject silos or more generally in everyday life. Saying that the aim of an English programme of study is not at least in part to support higher  attainment throughout the curriculum would fly in the face of just about every established education tradition. On team work and leadership, it rather depends on whether you think education is about isolating skills from the ways human beings work. If you think learning facts and instrumental skills is what constitute a rounded education fair enough but I certainly wouldn&#8217;t want my grandchildren taught like that. There is some clear precedence for assessing &#8220;social skills&#8221; in the context of science and technology. The Suffolk Science GCSE course had assessment weight given to effective collaboration between learners in experimental investigation and for good reason. Most major discoveries in science are made by teams, not individuals working in isolation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		Comment on Miranda&#8217;s ICT curriculum by Claire Johnson		</title>
		<link>https://www.mirandanet.org.uk/researchexchange/publications/articles/ict-curriculum-mirandas-views/our-ict-curriculum/comment-page-1/#comment-13415</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Claire Johnson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2012 23:33:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.mirandanet.ac.uk/researchexchange/?page_id=3102#comment-13415</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I think there is too much emphasis on ICT across the curriculum in the above. ICT is its own curriculum subject and comments about the use of ICT across the curriculum are not relevant to discussions of the PoS for ICT. eg &quot;Effectiveness will be  judged by how well all pupils use a range of contemporary technologies efficiently and effectively to routinely support their learning across the curriculum, preparing them to transfer this technological culture and capability to their future employment.&quot; That is not the concern of the PoS for ICT!
I also don&#039;t think there should be mention of &#039;leadership roles&#039; in the KS3 section. Neither is the need for pupils to come to a &#039;consensus&#039;appropriate.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I think there is too much emphasis on ICT across the curriculum in the above. ICT is its own curriculum subject and comments about the use of ICT across the curriculum are not relevant to discussions of the PoS for ICT. eg &#8220;Effectiveness will be  judged by how well all pupils use a range of contemporary technologies efficiently and effectively to routinely support their learning across the curriculum, preparing them to transfer this technological culture and capability to their future employment.&#8221; That is not the concern of the PoS for ICT!<br />
I also don&#8217;t think there should be mention of &#8216;leadership roles&#8217; in the KS3 section. Neither is the need for pupils to come to a &#8216;consensus&#8217;appropriate.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		Comment on ICT Curriculum Consultation by Jocelyn		</title>
		<link>https://www.mirandanet.org.uk/researchexchange/publications/articles/ict-curriculum-mirandas-views/ict-curriculum-consultation/comment-page-1/#comment-4982</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jocelyn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 14:06:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.mirandanet.ac.uk/researchexchange/?page_id=2883#comment-4982</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Christina asked us all for comments on the draft curriculum. Mine are organised by section below.

Aims &#038; Principles:  Include ‘safely’ in Can critically evaluate and apply information technology (including new or unfamiliar technologies) confidently, responsibly, collaboratively and effectively to solve problems and work creatively. 

Don’t understand purpose of including “Learn to see problems in computational terms” here.

KS1: Deep concern that “Understand what algorithms are and that these are implemented as programs on digital devices; use knowledge of algorithms to write simple programs.” is inappropriate language for both KS1 and their teachers – introducing pupils to logical sequencing and floor turtles, other toys is as far as I would go. If this is all that is actually intended then that needs to be said.

KS2: Concern re what would need to be taken out of the KS2 curriculum in order to spend the time that would be necessary to teach programming to the detail specified – there is too little at KS4 and too much here – more thought as to progression from child’s perspectives and abilities needed please. 

KS3: a clearer approach though uncertain as to what complex goals might be in “select, use and assemble multiple applications across a range of devices to achieve complex goals” . Should it be &quot;Recognise the impact of digital &lt;i&gt; and mobile &lt;/i&gt;technologies on society ?

KS4: Surprise as to “ethical, moral, legal and environmental aspects of information systems” in KS4, the differences between ethical and moral are nuanced and usually beyond me let alone a teenager – do we mean &#039;ethical and social&#039; which is the more common phrase? 

General concern throughout that without context and examples teachers will feel threatened by the new terminology and start teaching programming from non-age appropriate textbooks tentatively and badly. I am not seeing a ‘pupil voice’ in this – how can I show others what can I do with a computer, mobile phone etc.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Christina asked us all for comments on the draft curriculum. Mine are organised by section below.</p>
<p>Aims &amp; Principles:  Include ‘safely’ in Can critically evaluate and apply information technology (including new or unfamiliar technologies) confidently, responsibly, collaboratively and effectively to solve problems and work creatively. </p>
<p>Don’t understand purpose of including “Learn to see problems in computational terms” here.</p>
<p>KS1: Deep concern that “Understand what algorithms are and that these are implemented as programs on digital devices; use knowledge of algorithms to write simple programs.” is inappropriate language for both KS1 and their teachers – introducing pupils to logical sequencing and floor turtles, other toys is as far as I would go. If this is all that is actually intended then that needs to be said.</p>
<p>KS2: Concern re what would need to be taken out of the KS2 curriculum in order to spend the time that would be necessary to teach programming to the detail specified – there is too little at KS4 and too much here – more thought as to progression from child’s perspectives and abilities needed please. </p>
<p>KS3: a clearer approach though uncertain as to what complex goals might be in “select, use and assemble multiple applications across a range of devices to achieve complex goals” . Should it be &#8220;Recognise the impact of digital <i> and mobile </i>technologies on society ?</p>
<p>KS4: Surprise as to “ethical, moral, legal and environmental aspects of information systems” in KS4, the differences between ethical and moral are nuanced and usually beyond me let alone a teenager – do we mean &#8216;ethical and social&#8217; which is the more common phrase? </p>
<p>General concern throughout that without context and examples teachers will feel threatened by the new terminology and start teaching programming from non-age appropriate textbooks tentatively and badly. I am not seeing a ‘pupil voice’ in this – how can I show others what can I do with a computer, mobile phone etc.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		Comment on Is there really an alternative to Powerpoint? by Jeff		</title>
		<link>https://www.mirandanet.org.uk/researchexchange/publications/articles/building-and-sharing-professional-knowledge/is-there-an-alternative-to-powerpoint-really/comment-page-1/#comment-815</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 14:34:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.mirandanet.ac.uk/researchexchange/?page_id=1725#comment-815</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We tend to use Keynote even for a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thepowerpointagency.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;powerpoint slide design&lt;/a&gt; request from clients. it&#039;s so much more efficient for creation don&#039;t you think? As a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thepowerpointagency.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;powerpoint design company&lt;/a&gt; we have to work with Powerpoint but we would gladly give it up for other media.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We tend to use Keynote even for a <a href="http://www.thepowerpointagency.com" rel="nofollow">powerpoint slide design</a> request from clients. it&#8217;s so much more efficient for creation don&#8217;t you think? As a <a href="http://www.thepowerpointagency.com" rel="nofollow">powerpoint design company</a> we have to work with Powerpoint but we would gladly give it up for other media.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		Comment on Is there really an alternative to Powerpoint? by Ian Lynch		</title>
		<link>https://www.mirandanet.org.uk/researchexchange/publications/articles/building-and-sharing-professional-knowledge/is-there-an-alternative-to-powerpoint-really/comment-page-1/#comment-473</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ian Lynch]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2012 15:28:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.mirandanet.ac.uk/researchexchange/?page_id=1725#comment-473</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you want to share info. use Google docs http://bit.ly/L9WWHU  or some other app that uses web pages. Update the presentation and everyone gets it. Build links to integrate the info. with your other info. Stop filling your hard drive with thousands of files you&#039;ll never ever find!]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you want to share info. use Google docs <a href="http://bit.ly/L9WWHU" rel="nofollow ugc">http://bit.ly/L9WWHU</a>  or some other app that uses web pages. Update the presentation and everyone gets it. Build links to integrate the info. with your other info. Stop filling your hard drive with thousands of files you&#8217;ll never ever find!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		Comment on Critical incidents by Graham Galer		</title>
		<link>https://www.mirandanet.org.uk/researchexchange/events-2/research-themes/critical-incidentsexperiences-as-research-data/comment-page-1/#comment-36</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Graham Galer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2011 10:15:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.mirandanet.ac.uk/blog/?page_id=310#comment-36</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Here is one of my critical incidents - 

My first job in industry, in the late 1950s, was as a mathematical economist working on one of the early applications of computers to the planning of oil refineries and chemical plants.  The approach used was called &#039;linear programming&#039; (LP).  This technique (in our case) entailed identifying all the potential sales of the company&#039;s products  and the inputs required to produce those products.  A &#039;profit function&#039; was then defined based on the sales prices and the processing costs.  Then there were a series of  equations (&#039;constraints&#039;) representing the maximum quantity which could be sold of each product, the maximum capacity of each processing plant and the amount of input needed for each product.  The problem then was to &#039;maximise&#039; the profit subject to all the identified constraints, i.e. to find, out of all the possible ways of running the plant, the one which would give the greatest profit.  This was a mathematical problem which could be solved used well-tried techniques.

Our problems tended to have about 400 variables and 300 or so equations - too large to solve on a blackboard or a desk calculator but just about within the limits of the computers then becoming available.  The only computer my company had available at that time was in Amsterdam, and I and others used to go over there regularly with our LP problems, in the course of a few months establishing to our management that this approach was well worth developing.  The &#039;maximum&#039; profit programmes we came up with often produced results different from those which might have been arrived at using the traditional methods of hand calculation.

Sometimes Amsterdam was not available and we had to seek out alternative computer centres.  For a few months during 1958 we bought time at an IBM centre in the Place Vendome in Paris, and is was there that a &#039;critical incident&#039; occurred.  Our programmes were large and took a long time (e.g. several hours) to run (they would probably run in a few seconds on a modern laptop!)  So one could leave them &#039;cooking&#039; and go back to the hotel or out for a meal for a while.  I did this the time we used the IBM facility, returning after a while to the computer centre to see what had been produced.

Looking at the computer printout (which came out as several large sheets) I was baffled.  I didn&#039;t recognise this as a normal programme at all, although it seemed to have a certain logic about it.  What the computer was telling us was that we should produce the maximum amounts of the most expensive products, and put them into storage, rather than selling them.  What on earth was going on?

Looking at the programme in more detail, it was clear that, instead of maximising profit, the computer had worked out a way of minimising it.  Disaster!  How could this have happened?  I sat  down with colleagues and some of the IBM staff, going in detail into the programme, and into the way the problem had originally been fed into the machine.

After a while, it dawned on us: the computer programme had turned all our &#039;pluses&#039; into &#039;minuses&#039; and all our &#039;minuses&#039; into &#039;pluses&#039;. so that it &#039;thought&#039; that the sales proceeds we had defined were actually costs, and that our costs were the equivalent of sales proceeds.  It then did an excellent job if maximising the loss, i.e. minimising the profit.  It turned out that was due to differences beween the IBM programme we were using and the one we normally used in Amsterdam and elsewhere.

Fortunately no real harm was done, since the cost of one abortive run was not too high, and we were able to revise our input quite quickly.  In fact, the whole experience was quite educational, as the computer demonstrated some amazingly clever ways of potentially losing money for the company!

The thing that I and others learned from this critical incident was to be extremely careful to define what you are asking a computer to do - in the old adage: &#039;rubbish in, rubbish out&#039;.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Here is one of my critical incidents &#8211; </p>
<p>My first job in industry, in the late 1950s, was as a mathematical economist working on one of the early applications of computers to the planning of oil refineries and chemical plants.  The approach used was called &#8216;linear programming&#8217; (LP).  This technique (in our case) entailed identifying all the potential sales of the company&#8217;s products  and the inputs required to produce those products.  A &#8216;profit function&#8217; was then defined based on the sales prices and the processing costs.  Then there were a series of  equations (&#8216;constraints&#8217;) representing the maximum quantity which could be sold of each product, the maximum capacity of each processing plant and the amount of input needed for each product.  The problem then was to &#8216;maximise&#8217; the profit subject to all the identified constraints, i.e. to find, out of all the possible ways of running the plant, the one which would give the greatest profit.  This was a mathematical problem which could be solved used well-tried techniques.</p>
<p>Our problems tended to have about 400 variables and 300 or so equations &#8211; too large to solve on a blackboard or a desk calculator but just about within the limits of the computers then becoming available.  The only computer my company had available at that time was in Amsterdam, and I and others used to go over there regularly with our LP problems, in the course of a few months establishing to our management that this approach was well worth developing.  The &#8216;maximum&#8217; profit programmes we came up with often produced results different from those which might have been arrived at using the traditional methods of hand calculation.</p>
<p>Sometimes Amsterdam was not available and we had to seek out alternative computer centres.  For a few months during 1958 we bought time at an IBM centre in the Place Vendome in Paris, and is was there that a &#8216;critical incident&#8217; occurred.  Our programmes were large and took a long time (e.g. several hours) to run (they would probably run in a few seconds on a modern laptop!)  So one could leave them &#8216;cooking&#8217; and go back to the hotel or out for a meal for a while.  I did this the time we used the IBM facility, returning after a while to the computer centre to see what had been produced.</p>
<p>Looking at the computer printout (which came out as several large sheets) I was baffled.  I didn&#8217;t recognise this as a normal programme at all, although it seemed to have a certain logic about it.  What the computer was telling us was that we should produce the maximum amounts of the most expensive products, and put them into storage, rather than selling them.  What on earth was going on?</p>
<p>Looking at the programme in more detail, it was clear that, instead of maximising profit, the computer had worked out a way of minimising it.  Disaster!  How could this have happened?  I sat  down with colleagues and some of the IBM staff, going in detail into the programme, and into the way the problem had originally been fed into the machine.</p>
<p>After a while, it dawned on us: the computer programme had turned all our &#8216;pluses&#8217; into &#8216;minuses&#8217; and all our &#8216;minuses&#8217; into &#8216;pluses&#8217;. so that it &#8216;thought&#8217; that the sales proceeds we had defined were actually costs, and that our costs were the equivalent of sales proceeds.  It then did an excellent job if maximising the loss, i.e. minimising the profit.  It turned out that was due to differences beween the IBM programme we were using and the one we normally used in Amsterdam and elsewhere.</p>
<p>Fortunately no real harm was done, since the cost of one abortive run was not too high, and we were able to revise our input quite quickly.  In fact, the whole experience was quite educational, as the computer demonstrated some amazingly clever ways of potentially losing money for the company!</p>
<p>The thing that I and others learned from this critical incident was to be extremely careful to define what you are asking a computer to do &#8211; in the old adage: &#8216;rubbish in, rubbish out&#8217;.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
