<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>MirandaMods &#8211; MirandaNet Consultancy</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.mirandanet.org.uk/consultancy/category/mirandamods/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.mirandanet.org.uk/consultancy</link>
	<description>Educators supporting Educators</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2012 13:08:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.15</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Film and teacher driven CPD. How MirandaMods and TeachMeets promote professional reflection and good practice.</title>
		<link>https://www.mirandanet.org.uk/consultancy/2011/film-and-teacher-driven-cpd-how-teachmeets-and-mirandamods-are-one-of-the-best-and-most-cost-effective-resources-for-teacher-training-reflection-and-good-practice/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 15:47:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Consultancy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fellowship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MirandaMods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MirandaNet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.mirandanet.ac.uk/consultancy/?p=672</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[How TeachMeets and MirandaMods are one of the best and most cost-effective resources for teacher training, reflection and good practice. In the last five years I have been documenting the TeachMeet and MirandaMod phenomenons on film. I have now built &#8230; <a href="https://www.mirandanet.org.uk/consultancy/2011/film-and-teacher-driven-cpd-how-teachmeets-and-mirandamods-are-one-of-the-best-and-most-cost-effective-resources-for-teacher-training-reflection-and-good-practice/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>How TeachMeets and MirandaMods are one of the best and most cost-effective resources for teacher training, reflection and good practice.</strong></p>
<p>In the last five years I have been documenting the <a title="TeachMeet front page" href="http://teachmeet.pbworks.com/w/page/19975349/FrontPage" target="_blank">TeachMeet</a> and <a title="MirandaMods " href="http://mirandamod.wikispaces.com/Recent" target="_blank">MirandaMod</a> phenomenons on film.</p>
<p>I have now built up over 500 hours of film of teachers demonstrating, to other teachers, effective teaching and learning techniques.</p>
<p><strong>TEACHMEETS</strong></p>
<p><embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="680" height="570" src="http://blip.tv/play/gr8cgqHqBQA" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always"></embed></p>
<p>Each TeachMeet session consists of a number of teachers who have agreed to meet up (usually in the evening) and share best practice in either a seven or two minute presentation.</p>
<p>My role at each of these meets has been to live stream the video out for a wider audience much like a TV broadcast and to capture the sessions to film for free distribution later.</p>
<p>TeachMeets are extremely popular and growing in number. They are usually held in the evening towards the end of the school week or at weekends.</p>
<p><strong>COST EFFECTIVE CPD &#8211; IT&#8217;S POPULAR AND FREE!</strong></p>
<p>TeachMeets cost nothing for teachers or schools to put on, as all food, drink, accommodation and other publicity costs are increasingly paid for by commercial educational sponsors. The sponsors do not get to present but they do give out publicity matter and prizes for raffles. (e.g. a year&#8217;s free subscription to their services).</p>
<p>In many cases, as in the Blackpool Teachmeets last year, more teachers turned out for TeachMeet CPD than &#8220;official&#8221; scheduled LA CPD. This is increasingly becoming the norm &#8211; the main reasons for their popularity is that it that the CPD is coming from the teachers themselves and not the the LA advisers; the CPD is also a social event with food and drink and a chance to catch up with others on best practice. Teachers are often best placed to know more about current practice and innovative ways in which to reflect on and manage classroom teaching and learning so it is not surprising that this method of CPD has now caught on like wildfire.</p>
<p><strong>MIRANDAMODS</strong></p>
<p>I also film and archive MirandaMods which follow a similar pattern to TeachMeets except the films document longer and more reflective discussions.</p>
<p>People will discuss face to face and remotely the issues outlined in the MirandaMod sessions but also be able to amend documents in real time online as each session progresses.</p>
<p><strong>CPD IN HARD TO GET TO PLACES</strong></p>
<p>One of the main distinctions of MirandaMods over TeachMeets is that they are often broadcast from exhibitions or difficult to get to places for broadcast. I pride myself on being able to broadcast from almost anywhere in the country and with the most meagre of equipment. Last year I even managed to broadcast an educational discussion from a treehouse in the middle of Regents Park</p>
<p>Have a look at this broadcast from a table on a stand at the recent BETT show &#8211; the commercial partners, academics, teachers and others introduce themselves and the debate begins. Not only is the discussion going on face to face but also globally and all the notes and other exemplars are being gathered and sourced onto a collaboratively written document in real time saving hours of collating and dissemination.</p>
<p><embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="642" height="386" src="http://blip.tv/play/gr8cgb_zegA" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always"></embed></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>MirandaMods &#8211; Learning in Liminal Spaces</title>
		<link>https://www.mirandanet.org.uk/consultancy/2011/mirandamods/</link>
					<comments>https://www.mirandanet.org.uk/consultancy/2011/mirandamods/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 12:28:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[MirandaMods]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.mirandanet.ac.uk/consultancy/?p=221</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MirandaNet Fellows have become increasingly engaged in defining the process of learning collaboratively online and in storing the outcomes for other professionals to share. The crucible for our learning about these collaborative processes is the MirandaMod: an informal unconference that &#8230; <a href="https://www.mirandanet.org.uk/consultancy/2011/mirandamods/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>MirandaNet Fellows have become increasingly engaged in defining the process of learning collaboratively online and in storing the outcomes for other professionals to share. The crucible for our learning about these collaborative processes is the <a href="http://www.mirandanet.org.uk/mirandamods/">MirandaMod</a>: an informal unconference that takes place face to face and online simultaneously.  Not only are we engaged in analysing the practice of collaborative learning, but in developing an emerging knowledge building theory that we call ‘<a href="https://wec.mirandanet.org.uk/etopia_blog/?page_id=113">Braided Learning</a>’.</p>
<p>What we know so far is that informal dynamic knowledge creation in collaborative contexts occurs as participants move from textual debate in a conventional mailing list to video conferencing, micro blogging contributions and collaborative concept maps.</p>
<p>The informal dynamic knowledge creation in collaborative contexts occurs as participants move from textual debate in a conventional mailing list to video conferencing, micro blogging contributions and collaborative concept maps. This collaborative technology can be seen as creating a liminal space – a passage, in which a person moves from one state of being to another. Participants in this liminal space are transformed by acquiring new knowledge, a new status and a new identity in the community. This change is of critical importance if learning is to be successful. Whilst remote and informal learning is largely is what has been understood about mobile learning, the concept can now be extended to include these informal spaces in which learning takes place – the liminal spaces that those who push the boundaries of digital possibilities now inhabit intellectually (Cuthell, Preston, Kuechel and Cych, 2009).</p>
<p>The paper aims to extend understanding of liminal spaces and their contribution to the learning process. Evidence from participants from the United Kingdom, Europe, West Africa, the United States and Australasia is used to estimate the value of such informal learning for professionals. The qualitative and quantitative research tools that record both the numbers involved in the different activities, levels of participation and the extent of the professional knowledge created are identified. The processes can be described as Bricolage (Levi Strauss, 1962), in which people build new knowledge from what is at hand. Some consideration is given to the long-term impact of building professional knowledge in a range of media that are not subject to conventional peer review. Finally the advantages and disadvantages of informal learning against formal learning are summarised.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.virtuallearning.org.uk/?page_id=548">Read more.</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.mirandanet.org.uk/consultancy/2011/mirandamods/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
