<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: Miranda&#8217;s ICT curriculum	</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.mirandanet.org.uk/researchexchange/publications/articles/ict-curriculum-mirandas-views/our-ict-curriculum/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.mirandanet.org.uk/researchexchange</link>
	<description>O brave new world that has such people in IT</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2014 17:10:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.15</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		By: Ian Lynch		</title>
		<link>https://www.mirandanet.org.uk/researchexchange/publications/articles/ict-curriculum-mirandas-views/our-ict-curriculum/comment-page-1/#comment-15687</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ian Lynch]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 10:40:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.mirandanet.ac.uk/researchexchange/?page_id=3102#comment-15687</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There is no mention of using ICT across the curriculum although I doubt it would be any more sensible not to do so than say isolate English to just specialist lessons. Digital technologies are useless without application. Why learn any technology if it does not result in a practical outcome? That principle applies to computing except perhaps for blue sky research in number theories which has a tiny minority of relevance in schools and would probably be better in the maths department. Even school science departments understand that purely theoretical science has a very limited place in high schools. That is not to say digital technologies do not need specialist input - again English is a good parallel. Learning English is not much use if it does not practically contribute to being able to communicate whether in subject silos or more generally in everyday life. Saying that the aim of an English programme of study is not at least in part to support higher  attainment throughout the curriculum would fly in the face of just about every established education tradition. On team work and leadership, it rather depends on whether you think education is about isolating skills from the ways human beings work. If you think learning facts and instrumental skills is what constitute a rounded education fair enough but I certainly wouldn&#039;t want my grandchildren taught like that. There is some clear precedence for assessing &quot;social skills&quot; in the context of science and technology. The Suffolk Science GCSE course had assessment weight given to effective collaboration between learners in experimental investigation and for good reason. Most major discoveries in science are made by teams, not individuals working in isolation.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There is no mention of using ICT across the curriculum although I doubt it would be any more sensible not to do so than say isolate English to just specialist lessons. Digital technologies are useless without application. Why learn any technology if it does not result in a practical outcome? That principle applies to computing except perhaps for blue sky research in number theories which has a tiny minority of relevance in schools and would probably be better in the maths department. Even school science departments understand that purely theoretical science has a very limited place in high schools. That is not to say digital technologies do not need specialist input &#8211; again English is a good parallel. Learning English is not much use if it does not practically contribute to being able to communicate whether in subject silos or more generally in everyday life. Saying that the aim of an English programme of study is not at least in part to support higher  attainment throughout the curriculum would fly in the face of just about every established education tradition. On team work and leadership, it rather depends on whether you think education is about isolating skills from the ways human beings work. If you think learning facts and instrumental skills is what constitute a rounded education fair enough but I certainly wouldn&#8217;t want my grandchildren taught like that. There is some clear precedence for assessing &#8220;social skills&#8221; in the context of science and technology. The Suffolk Science GCSE course had assessment weight given to effective collaboration between learners in experimental investigation and for good reason. Most major discoveries in science are made by teams, not individuals working in isolation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Claire Johnson		</title>
		<link>https://www.mirandanet.org.uk/researchexchange/publications/articles/ict-curriculum-mirandas-views/our-ict-curriculum/comment-page-1/#comment-13415</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Claire Johnson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2012 23:33:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.mirandanet.ac.uk/researchexchange/?page_id=3102#comment-13415</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I think there is too much emphasis on ICT across the curriculum in the above. ICT is its own curriculum subject and comments about the use of ICT across the curriculum are not relevant to discussions of the PoS for ICT. eg &quot;Effectiveness will be  judged by how well all pupils use a range of contemporary technologies efficiently and effectively to routinely support their learning across the curriculum, preparing them to transfer this technological culture and capability to their future employment.&quot; That is not the concern of the PoS for ICT!
I also don&#039;t think there should be mention of &#039;leadership roles&#039; in the KS3 section. Neither is the need for pupils to come to a &#039;consensus&#039;appropriate.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I think there is too much emphasis on ICT across the curriculum in the above. ICT is its own curriculum subject and comments about the use of ICT across the curriculum are not relevant to discussions of the PoS for ICT. eg &#8220;Effectiveness will be  judged by how well all pupils use a range of contemporary technologies efficiently and effectively to routinely support their learning across the curriculum, preparing them to transfer this technological culture and capability to their future employment.&#8221; That is not the concern of the PoS for ICT!<br />
I also don&#8217;t think there should be mention of &#8216;leadership roles&#8217; in the KS3 section. Neither is the need for pupils to come to a &#8216;consensus&#8217;appropriate.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
