<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>MirandaNet Research Exchange</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.mirandanet.org.uk/researchexchange/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.mirandanet.org.uk/researchexchange</link>
	<description>O brave new world that has such people in IT</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2012 11:00:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.15</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Welcome to the Future Learning Research Exchange</title>
		<link>https://www.mirandanet.org.uk/researchexchange/2010/238/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christina Preston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2010 12:24:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ICT CPD]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.mirandanet.ac.uk/blog/?p=238</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A place for investigating and commenting into research into Continuing Professional Development(CPD) for teachers focusing on the value of digital technologies in teaching and learning.  <a href="https://www.mirandanet.org.uk/researchexchange/2010/238/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>&#8216;O brave new world, that has such people in IT!&#8217;</em></p>
<p>The Future Learning research exchange represents a partnership between:</p>
<ul>
<li>The MirandaNet Fellowship;</li>
<li>Learning Futures Research Centre, Institute of Research into Education (IREd) University of Bedfordshire;</li>
<li> The Education Futures Collaboration.</li>
</ul>
<p>The aim of this research think tank is to influence policy on educational innovation through evidence. The discussions and research findings developed between researchers, educators, policy makers and companies about digital technologies in education are used to guide the informed management of systemic changes in schools and teacher education. The partnership reflects the exponential changes in the ownership of knowledge throughout the world and aims to raise the status of professional knowledge about teaching and learning.</p>
<p>So far the <a href="/researchexchange/about-the-team/" target="_blank">Education Innovation team</a> is establishing a research reputation for studies of: emergent theory and practice collaborative knowledge creation  in  <a title="Communities of practice" href="www.mirandanet.org.uk/blog/?page_id=368">communities of practice</a> that we call  <a href="http://www.mirandanet.org.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/Braided-Learning-First-Monday-2007-.doc">Braided Learning</a>. We also conduct research into the value of <a href="/researchexchange/critical-incidentsexperiences-as-research-data/">concept maps</a> and <a href="researchexchange/critical-incidentsexperiences-as-research-data/">critical incidents</a> as a data collection tools. In this  space we share our research ideas, knowledge, methods and publications with any colleagues who are looking for synergies. Lively debate is welcome.</p>
<p>Here you will find  summaries of relevant discussions by <a href="http://www.mirandanet.org.uk/fellowship/" target="_blank">MirandaNet members </a>from our internal debating forum called mirandalink; abstracts of articles and  <a href="/researchexchange/publications/" target="_blank">publications</a>. Members can join in our face to face and virtual meetings in knowledge creation  at our regular <a title="MirandaMod" href="http://www.mirandanet.org.uk/mirandamods">MirandaMod</a> unconferences and events. Researchers can also apply for drafts of our work that has not been published yet or is restricted to our members only.</p>
<p>What would you like to add? Researchers can publish summaries of their thesis, articles and papers here subject to peer review. Any scholar who publishes on MirandaNet receives a Fellowship and for subsequent publications and contributions to activities a Senior Fellowship. Members who take on executive roles are awarded a MirandaNet Ambassador title. Details of awards members can win are <a href="http://www.mirandanet.org.uk/fellowship/">here</a>.</p>
<p>Professor Christina Preston, Professor of Educational Innovation, University of Bedfordshire and founder of MirandaNet Fellowship: &#99;&#x68;&#x72;i&#115;&#x74;i&#110;&#x61;&#x40;&#109;&#x69;&#x72;a&#110;&#x64;a&#110;&#x65;&#x74;&#46;&#x61;&#x63;&#46;&#117;&#x6b;.</p>
<p>Links</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.mirandanet.ac.uk">The MirandaNet Fellowship</a>;</li>
<li><a href="www.beds.ac.uk/research/ired">Learning Futures Research Centre, Institute of Research into Education (IREd) University of Bedfordshire</a>;</li>
<li> <a href="http://www.mirandanet.org.uk/researchexchange/education-communities/">The Education Futures Collaboration</a>.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
